A Guide to the Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files, 1981-1982
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files 1981-1982
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-2/1/2.841
This collection consists of 14,400 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred to the library on 1984 June 22.
Scope and Content Information
These files constitute the major record series generated by the president of the University of Virginia. The records consist chiefly of correspondence, but also include reports, minutes, clippings, memoranda, and related papers concerning all areas of business of the president's office.
The papers consist of: general files, 1981-1982; permanent files, 1969-1982; and, committee files, 1981-1982.
Organization
Series I: General Files, 1981-1982 Boxes 1-27
Series II: Administrative Committees Files, 1981-1982 Boxes 27-28
Series III: Permanent Files, 1960-1983 Boxes 29-35
Series IV: Restricted Material, 1981-1982 Box 36
Contents List
- Series I: General Records
  - "A-Al" Miscellaneous--Gifts, Agrigenetics, Albemarle County Government, Richard V. Allen 1981-1982 (Box 1)
  - "Am" Miscellaneous 1981-1982 (Box 1)
  - "An-Az" Miscellaneous--Gifts, Apple Computers, Malvinas/Falkland Islands 1981-1982 (Box 1)
  - Admissions--General 1981-1982 (Box 1)
  - Admissions--Law 1981-1982 (Box 1)
  - Afro-American Affairs 1981-1982 (Box 1)
  - Afro-American and African Studies--Woodson Institute--Woodson Institute Dedication Ceremonies 1981-1982 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Association--General 1981-1982 (Box 1)
  - American Association of University Professors 1981-1982 (Box 1)
  - American Council on Education--Federal Legislation 1981-1982 (Box 2)
  - Annual Report--President's Report 1981-1982 (Box 2)
  - Anthropology 1981-1982 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions "A-Z" 1981-1982 (Box 2)
  - Architecture--Lecture Schedules, Gifts 1981-1982 (Box 2)
  - Art--General 1981-1982 (Box 2)
  - Art--Bayly Art Museum--Landscaping Plans, Gifts 1981-1982 (Box 2)
  - Asian Studies 1981-1982 (Box 2)
  - Associated Western Universities 1981-1982 (Box 2)
  - Association of American Colleges 1981-1982 (Box 2)
  - Association of American Universities--Federal Legislation (1 of 4) 1981-1982 (Box 2)
  - Association of American Universities--Federal Funding, Department of Defense (2-4 of 4) 1981-1982 (Box 3)
  - Association of Virginia Colleges 1981-1982 (Box 3)
  - Astronomy 1981-1982 (Box 3)
  - Athletics--General--Birdwood, VSAF Donations (1 of 2) 1981-1982 (Box 4)
  - Athletics--General--Pep Band, Intramurals (2 of 2) 1981-1982 (Box 4)
  - Athletics--ACC--TV Contracts with CBS, Constitution and Bylaws 1981-1982 (Box 4)
  - Athletics--CFA (2 folders) 1981-1982 (Box 4)
  - Athletics--NCAA 1981-1982 (Box 4)
  - Attorney General--State--Liability Insurance 1981-1982 (Box 4)
  - Auditor--Internal (2 folders) 1981-1982 (Box 5)
  - Auditor of Public Accounts 1981-1982 (Box 5)
  - "Ba-Bm" Miscellaneous--Gifts, ABC 'Nightline', Rare Books Library 1981-1982 (Box 5)
  - "Bn-Bz" Miscellaneous--Gifts, Commencement Unruliness, Bursar 1981-1982 (Box 5)
  - Biology--General 1981-1982 (Box 6)
  - Business and Finance--Public Disclosure of Salaries, Vincent Estate, Fontaine Property 1981-1982 (Box 6)
  - Business Operations--Birdwood, Air Charter Service 1981-1982 (Box 6)
  - "Ca-Cg" Miscellaneous--Gifts, Funding in Higher Education, Camp Foundation 1981-1982 (Box 6)
  - "Ch-Cn" Miscellaneous--Gifts, FAA Regulations, Charlottesville-Albemarle Rescue Squad 1981-1982 (Box 6)
  - "Co-Cz" Miscellaneous--Gifts, Collins Estate, U.S. Congress, Currie Property 1981-1982 (Box 7)
  - Career Planning and Placement 1981-1982 (Box 7)
  - Cavalier Daily 1981-1982 (Box 7)
  - Charlottesville, City of 1981-1982 (Box 7)
  - Chemistry 1981-1982 (Box 7)
  - Civil Rights 1981-1982 (Box 7)
  - Classics 1981-1982 (Box 7)
  - Clinch Valley College--Surface Mining 1981-1982 (Box 7)
  - College of Arts and Sciences--Garret Hall Use 1981-1982 (Box 7)
  - College Entrance Exam Boards 1981-1982 (Box 7)
  - Commerce 1981-1982 (Box 7)
  - Community Colleges 1981-1982 (Box 8)
  - Comptroller--State 1981-1982 (Box 8)
  - Computing and Communications (2 folders) 1981-1982 (Box 8)
  - Consortia--Central Virginia 1981-1982 (Box 8)
  - Consortia--Northern Virginia (1 of 2) 1981-1982 (Box 8)
  - Consortia--Northern Virginia (2 of 2) 1981-1982 (Box 9)
  - Consortia--Tidewater 1981-1982 (Box 9)
  - Consortia--Valley 1981-1982 (Box 9)
  - Consortia--Western 1981-1982 (Box 9)
  - Continuing Education--Elder Hostel, French Restaurant School, Summer on the Lawn 1981-1982 (Box 9)
  - Council of Presidents 1981-1982 (Box 9)
  - Council of Southern Universities--Diuguid Fellowships 1981-1982 (Box 9)
  - "D" Miscellaneous--Gifts (2 folders) 1981-1982 (Box 9)
  - Darden Business Sponsors--Minutes 1981-1982 (Box 9)
  - Darden Graduate School of Business Administration--Chaired Professors, Admission Statistics 1981-1982 (Box 9)
  - Dean's Meeting 1981-1982 (Box 9)
  - Development--General 1981-1982 (Box 9)
  - Drama--Heritage Repertory Theatre 1981-1982 (Box 9)
  - "E" Miscellaneous--Gifts, U.S. Department of Education 1981-1982 (Box 10)
  - Economics 1981-1982 (Box 10)
  - Education 1981-1982 (Box 10)
  - Energy Policy Studies Center 1981-1982 (Box 10)
  - Engineering and Applied Science--Accreditation, Grants 1981-1982 (Box 10)
  - Engineering and Buildings--Preplanning Justification (1 of 2) 1981-1982 (Box 10)
  - Engineering and Buildings--Preplanning Justification (2 of 2) 1981-1982 (Box 11)
  - Engineering and Buildings--State 1981-1982 (Box 11)
  - English 1981-1982 (Box 11)
  - Environmental Sciences 1981-1982 (Box 11)
  - Equal Opportunity--General 1981-1982 (Box 11)
  - "F" Miscellaneous--Gifts, Major Events Calendar, Farrish Fund 1981-1982 (Box 11)
  - Faculty--General 1981-1982 (Box 11)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences 1981-1982 (Box 11)
  - Financial Aid to Students--Federal Cuts 1981-1982 (Box 11)
  - Food Services 1981-1982 (Box 11)
  - French Literature and Linguistics 1981-1982 (Box 11)
  - "G" Miscellaneous--Gifts, Colgate Darden Memorial Convocation, General Electric Foundation, U.Va. Anecdotes ("Gilmore, J.L.") 1981-1982 (Box 12)
  - General Assembly--Legislative Impact Statement (1 of 2) 1981-1982 (Box 12)
  - General Assembly--Proposed Bills, Legislative Summaries (2 of 2) 1981-1982 (Box 12)
  - General Assembly--House Appropriations 1981-1982 (Box 12)
  - General Service--State 1981-1982 (Box 12)
  - German 1981-1982 (Box 12)
  - Gifts and Grants (3 folders) 1981-1982 (Box 13)
  - Government and Foreign Affairs 1981-1982 (Box 13)
  - Governor's Office--General 1981-1982 (Box 13)
  - Governor's Office--Administration and Finance 1981-1982 (Box 14)
  - Governor's Office--Commerce and Resources 1981-1982 (Box 14)
  - Governor's Office--Education 1981-1982 (Box 14)
  - Governor's Office--Human Resources 1981-1982 (Box 14)
  - Governor's Office--Transportation and General Safety (empty) 1981-1982 (Box 14)
  - Governor's Office--Washington Liaison Office 1981-1982 (Box 14)
  - Graduate School of Arts and Sciences--Solicitations, Out-of-State Ph.D.s remaining in Virginia (Sample) 1981-1982 (Box 14)
  - Graduate School of Arts and Sciences--Advisory Committee on Career Opportunities--Career Opportunities Institute for Ph.D.s 1981-1982 (Box 14)
  - "H" Miscellaneous--Gifts, Commencement Disruption, Charlottesville-Albemarle Metropolitan Planning Organization 1981-1982 (Box 14)
  - Hereford, Frank L. Jr.--Personal 1981-1982 (Box 14)
  - History--Sino-American Relations 1981-1982 (Box 14)
  - Honor System and Committee 1981-1982 (Box 15)
  - Housing 1981-1982 (Box 15)
  - "I" Miscellaneous--Gifts, International Studies 1981-1982 (Box 15)
  - Institute of Government--Local Government Officials' Conference, Constitution Bicentennial 1981-1982 (Box 15)
  - International Students 1981-1982 (Box 15)
  - "J" Miscellaneous--Gifts, Birdwood Golf Course (Jones, A.W.) 1981-1982 (Box 15)
  - Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation 1981-1982 (Box 15)
  - Joint Legislative Audit and Review Commission (JLARC) 1981-1982 (Box 15)
  - "K" Miscellaneous--Gifts, Proposed Kiosks 1981-1982 (Box 15)
  - "L" Miscellaneous--Gifts, U.Va. Historic Districts (Langhorne Trust) 1981-1982 (Box 15)
  - Law--General--Policy on Part-Time Students, Center for Oceans Law and Policy 1981-1982 (Box 15)
  - Lawn Society--Meeting 1981-1982 (Box 16)
  - Legal--General--Faulkner mss., ABC license, Steinmarc/Paramount Coal Corporation 1981-1982 (Box 16)
  - Library--General--Address by T.A. Graves to the Associates 1981-1982 (Box 16)
  - "Mc" Miscellaneous--Gifts 1981-1982 (Box 16)
  - "Ma-Me" Miscellaneous--Gifts, Dumas Malone Dinner 1981-1982 (Box 16)
  - "Mi-Mz" Miscellaneous--Gifts 1981-1982 (Box 16)
  - Management Analysis and Systems Development (MASD) 1981-1982 (Box 17)
  - Marine Science--Consortium Grant Proposal 1981-1982 (Box 17)
  - Mariners' Museum--Reports, Budgets, Master Plan (2 folders) 1981-1982 (Box 17)
  - Mathematics 1981-1982 (Box 18)
  - Medical Center--General--Heliport, Records Retention, Sears Building Renovations, Mission Statement 1981-1982 (Box 18)
  - Medical Center--Personnel 1981-1982 (Box 18)
  - Medical Center--Planning--Capital Outlay Projects, Status of Projects Under Construction 1981-1982 (Box 18)
  - Medical Center--Hospital--General--Hospital Information System Project, 5-year Plan for Data Processing, Proposed HMO, Admissions Criteria (Weaver), Indigent Care by County 1981-1982 (Box 18)
  - Medical Center--Medical School--General--Accreditation Site Visit 1981-1982 (Box 18)
  - Medical Center--Medical School--Personnel 1981-1982 (Box 18)
  - Medical Center--Nursing--General--Ph.D., Nursing Shortage 1981-1982 (Box 18)
  - Medical Center--Nursing--Personnel 1981-1982 (Box 18)
  - Music 1981-1982 (Box 18)
  - "N" Miscellaneous--Gifts, NEH Jefferson Lecture in the Humanities (1 of 2) 1981-1982 (Box 18)
  - "N" Miscellaneous--Gifts, New York Times Guide Ranking U.Va., North Carolina vs. Department of Education Consent Decree (2 of 2) 1981-1982 (Box 19)
  - National Association of State University and Land Grant Colleges 1981-1982 (Box 19)
  - National Science Foundation 1981-1982 (Box 19)
  - Newcomb Hall--Bank 1981-1982 (Box 19)
  - "O" Miscellaneous--Gifts, Oak Ridge Associated Universities 1981-1982 (Box 19)
  - Omicron Delta Kappa 1981-1982 (Box 19)
  - "P" Miscellaneous--Gifts (2 folders) 1981-1982 (Box 19)
  - Parking and Transportation--Car Rental Rates, Complaints, Lighting 1981-1982 (Box 19)
  - Personnel--General--Staff Development, Layoff Policy, Salary Structure 1981-1982 (Box 19)
  - Personnel and Training--State--Policies and Directives 1981-1982 (Box 20)
  - Physical Planning--Procurement, Real Estate 1981-1982 (Box 20)
  - Physical Plant--Budget and Capital Outlay Reports, Building Committee Appointments and Procedures (1 of 2) 1981-1982 (Box 20)
  - Physical Plant--Financial Reports, Montebello Reports and Drawings (2 of 2) 1981-1982 (Box 20)
  - Physical Plant--Research Renovations--Status Reports 1981-1982 (Box 20)
  - Physics--Jesse Beams Memorial, "New Horizons in Electromagnetic Physics" Conference 1981-1982 (Box 21)
  - Planning--Miscellaneous--Property Evaluation of Sites Adjacent to U.Va. (with plats), Faulkner Housing Project 1981-1982 (Box 21)
  - Planning--Project Status Reports 1981-1982 (Box 21)
  - Planning and Budget--Capital Outlay 1981-1982 (Box 21)
  - Planning and Budget--State--General Condition of U.Va. Facilities 1981-1982 (Box 21)
  - Planning and Budget--University 1981-1982 (Box 21)
  - Promotions 1981-1982 (Box 21)
  - Provost--Planning Goals, Library Book Budget, Policy Statements, Space Facilities Report 1981-1982 (Box 21)
  - Provost--Associate Provost for Research--Principal Duties 1981-1982 (Box 22)
  - Psychology 1981-1982 (Box 22)
  - Purchases and Supply 1981-1982 (Box 22)
  - Purchasing--Air Charter Proposal, Procurement Review 1981-1982 (Box 22)
  - "Q" Miscellaneous 1981-1982 (Box 22)
  - "R" Miscellaneous--Gifts, Commencement Unruliness (Rawlings), Risk Management, Charles S. Robb, Russell Estate 1981-1982 (Box 22)
  - Recommendations "A-Z" 1981-1982 (Box 22)
  - Registrar--Class Scheduling 1981-1982 (Box 22)
  - Religious Studies 1981-1982 (Box 22)
  - Resource and Policy Studies--Student Information System, Summaries of Students and Staff, Student Credit Hour/FTE Faculty Study, Faculty Salary Studies 1981-1982 (Box 22)
  - Risk Management 1981-1982 (Box 23)
  - ROTC--General 1981-1982 (Box 23)
  - ROTC--Air Force 1981-1982 (Box 23)
  - ROTC--Army 1981-1982 (Box 23)
  - ROTC--Navy 1981-1982 (Box 23)
  - "Sa-Sl" Miscellaneous--Gifts, Hugh Scott 1981-1982 (Box 23)
  - "Sm-Sz" Miscellaneous--Gifts, South Africa, Stone and Webster/ Nuclear Engineering 1981-1982 (Box 23)
  - Sociology 1981-1982 (Box 24)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools 1981-1982 (Box 24)
  - Southern Association of Land Grant Colleges and State Universities 1981-1982 (Box 24)
  - Space and Energy Management--Building Values 1981-1982 (Box 24)
  - Spanish, Italian, and Portuguese--Language House 1981-1982 (Box 24)
  - Speeches--Current--Clemons Library Dedication, Colgate Darden Convocation, University and Alumni Functions 1981-1982 (Box 24)
  - Sponsored Programs--Proposal and Award Summary 1981-1982 (Box 24)
  - State Council of Higher Education (SCHE)--FTE Faculty and Staff Calculations, Issue Papers (1 of 4) 1981-1982 (Box 24)
  - State Council of Higher Education (SCHE)--Issue Papers (2 of 4) 1981-1982 (Box 24)
  - State Council of Higher Education (SCHE)--Issue Papers, Report on Off-Campus Instruction (3 of 4) 1981-1982 (Box 24)
  - State Council of Higher Education (SCHE)--Report on Off-Campus Instruction, Briefing Papers (4 of 4) 1981-1982 (Box 25)
  - State Council of Higher Education (SCHE)--Council Notes 1981-1982 (Box 25)
  - State Department of Education 1981-1982 (Box 25)
  - State Fire Marshall 1981-1982 (Box 25)
  - Student Affairs--Fraternity/Sorority Stats, Kiosks, Safety, President's Retreat Evaluation Report, Hazing (1 of 2) 1981-1982 (Box 25)
  - Student Affairs--Unruliness (Feb 20), Judicial System Reform (Apr 26), Corks and Curls autonomy (May 21), Finals Ceremony (June), "Summary of Responses to the 1981 American Council of Education Survey" (June 21) (2 of 2) 1981-1982 (Box 25)
  - Student Council--Investment Policy research Committee, Safety Awareness 1981-1982 (Box 25)
  - Student Council--Minutes 1981-1982 (Box 25)
  - Summer Session--Statistics and Cost/Income Analyses 1981-1982 (Box 26)
  - "T" Miscellaneous--Gifts, Audio-Visual Technology 1981-1982 (Box 26)
  - Tayloe Murphy Institute 1981-1982 (Box 26)
  - Travel Invoices 1981-1982 (Box 26)
  - Treasurer 1981-1982 (Box 26)
  - "U" Miscellaneous 1981-1982 (Box 26)
  - U.S. Savings Bonds 1981-1982 (Box 26)
  - United Way 1981-1982 (Box 26)
  - Universities Research Association 1981-1982 (Box 26)
  - University Guides 1981-1982 (Box 26)
  - University Police 1981-1982 (Box 26)
  - University Press of Virginia 1981-1982 (Box 26)
  - University Relations 1981-1982 (Box 26)
  - University Union 1981-1982 (Box 26)
  - "V" Miscellaneous--Gifts, U.Va. Publications Inventory (Virginia State Library) 1981-1982 (Box 27)
  - Virginia Academy of Science 1981-1982 (Box 27)
  - Virginia Student Aid Foundation 1981-1982 (Box 27)
  - "Wa-Wh" Miscellaneous--Gifts, Warner, John W. 1981-1982 (Box 27)
  - "Wi-Wz" Miscellaneous--Gifts 1981-1982 (Box 27)
  - "X-Y-Z" Miscellaneous--Gifts 1981-1982 (Box 27)
- Series II: Administrative Committees
  - Administrative--General 1981-1982 (Box 27)
  - Admissions 1981-1982 (Box 27)
  - Afro-American Affairs Advisory 1981-1982 (Box 27)
  - Algernon Sydney Sullivan Award 1981-1982 (Box 27)
  - Arboretum 1981-1982 (Box 27)
  - Architectural Advisory 1981-1982 (Box 27)
  - Athletic Advisory Council 1981-1982 (Box 27)
  - Bayly Museum 1981-1982 (Box 27)
  - Calendar 1981-1982 (Box 27)
  - Cemetery 1981-1982 (Box 27)
  - Chapel 1981-1982 (Box 27)
  - Chemical and Biological Hazards Safety 1981-1982 (Box 27)
  - Commencement and Convocations--Processions 1981-1982 (Box 27)
  - Commencement and Convocations--Public Occasions 1981-1982 (Box 27)
  - Community 1981-1982 (Box 28)
  - Computers 1981-1982 (Box 28)
  - Development Steering 1981-1982 (Box 28)
  - Education and Employment Opportunities, Obligations, and Rights 1981-1982 (Box 28)
  - Energy Conservation 1981-1982 (Box 28)
  - External Prizes and Awards 1981-1982 (Box 28)
  - Fraternities and Sororities 1981-1982 (Box 28)
  - Graduate Opportunities 1981-1982 (Box 28)
  - Graphics 1981-1982 (Box 28)
  - Gwathmey Award 1981-1982 (Box 28)
  - Housing 1981-1982 (Box 28)
  - International Students 1981-1982 (Box 28)
  - Thomas Jefferson Award 1981-1982 (Box 28)
  - Library 1981-1982 (Box 28)
  - Master Plan 1981-1982 (Box 28)
  - Names 1981-1982 (Box 28)
  - Radiation Safety 1981-1982 (Box 28)
  - Registration 1981-1982 (Box 28)
  - Residential Life 1981-1982 (Box 28)
  - Rhodes Scholarship 1981-1982 (Box 28)
  - ROTC 1981-1982 (Box 28)
  - Scheduling 1981-1982 (Box 28)
  - Scholarships, Grants-in-Aid, Employment and Loans 1981-1982 (Box 28)
  - Security and General Safety 1981-1982 (Box 28)
  - Student Activities 1981-1982 (Box 28)
  - Student Health 1981-1982 (Box 28)
  - Summer Grants 1981-1982 (Box 28)
  - Summer Sessions 1981-1982 (Box 28)
  - Traffic Appeals 1981-1982 (Box 28)
  - Traffic and Parking 1981-1982 (Box 28)
  - Truman Scholarship 1981-1982 (Box 28)
  - University Committee on Students 1981-1982 (Box 28)
  - University Press 1981-1982 (Box 28)
  - University Union 1981-1982 (Box 28)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review 1981-1982 (Box 28)
  - Virginia Status on University Students 1981-1982 (Box 28)
- Series III: Permanent Files
  - Anonymous Letter--Crank Mail (2 folders) 1977-1983 (Box 29)
  - Applications for Administrative Positions 1973 Oct-1981 Nov (Box 29)
  - Auditor--Internal 1970 Jul-1981 Feb (Box 29)
  - Condolences "A-E" 1973-1981 (Box 29)
  - Condolences "F-Z" (2 folders) 1973-1981 (Box 30)
  - Faculty--University Tenure--Policy of the University re: Academic Freedom 1960 Feb-1973 Jun (Box 30)
  - Faculty--Visiting Scholars 1972 Sep-1974 Jul (Box 30)
  - Faculty Housing Revenue Bonds 1972 (Box 30)
  - Faculty Orientation and Benefits (2 folders) 1971 May-1981 Nov (Box 30)
  - Institutional Planning and Studies--Executive Summaries 1977 Mar-1982 May (Box 31)
  - Medical Center--Blue Ridge Sanitorium (3 folders) 1975 Aug-1980 Sep (Box 31)
  - Medical Center--Master Plan (1 of 2) 1978 Aug-1980 Dec (Box 31)
  - Medical Center--Master Plan (2 of 2) 1978 Aug-1980 Dec (Box 32)
  - Medical Center--Primary Care Facility (2 folders) 1974 Apr-1981 Feb (Box 32)
  - Medical Center--Towers (3 folders) 1975 Jan-1982 Jun (Box 32)
  - Memos (2 folders) 1968 Apr-1980 Dec (Box 33)
  - National Medal of Science 1963 Apr-1980 May (Box 33)
  - Office Information 1969 Oct-1980 Jul (Box 33)
  - Office Information--Copy Machines 1975 Sep-1983 Feb (Box 33)
  - Office Information--Parking 1965 Aug-1978 Sep (Box 33)
  - Office Information--Telephone Systems 1974 Jul-1982 Jun (Box 33)
  - Patent Foundation 1976 Nov-1977 Nov (Box 34)
  - Patent Foundation--Proposal for U.Va. Alumni 1976 (Box 34)
  - Planning--Physical Planning Review Committee (2 folders) 1975 Dec-1982 Apr (Box 34)
  - Planning and Budget--Capital Outlay 1975 Oct-1976 Jan (Box 35)
  - Polo Building 1979 (Box 35)
  - Research and Policy Council (2 folders) 1971 Mar-1978 Aug (Box 35)
  - Space Utilization 1969-1973 (Box 35)
  - Student Affairs--Media Board 1976 Mar-1980 Jun (Box 35)
  - Terrace Bowling Building 1979 May-1980 Jul (Box 35)
  - Vepco Contract--Residential Housing 1980 (Box 35)
- Series IV: Restricted Material (Box 36)